翻译     杏仁斯嘉丽   SophiaSaaaga   *PiPi*
翻译     煮粥博士   承包瑞秋草
校对     魔法草
时间轴     噃噃Master   安斯Master   大圣法师
时间轴     Dr.shuanglu   倩倩硕士   贝壳博士
后期     8T
总监     somehacker   草草
卡西利亚斯法师
Master Kaecilius.
那个法事只会让你懊悔
That ritual will bring you only sorrow.
虚伪
Hypocrite!
挑战关卡  比利
Challenge round, Billy.
拜托  比利  开玩笑呢
Come on, Billy. You've got to be messing with me.
没有  医生
No, doctor.
《如此美好》  恰克·曼吉欧尼  1977年
Feels So Good, Chuck Mangione, 1977.
真是的  比利  你还说这个会很难呢
Honestly, Billy, you said this one would be hard.
-是1978年  -不  比利
- It's 1978. - No, Billy,
《如此美好》虽然是1978年登上榜单的
while Feels So Good may have charted in 1978,
但专辑是1977年12月发行的
the album was released in December, 1977.
-不  维基上说是197...  -再看看
- No, no. Wikipedia says it's a 19... - Check again.
这些无用的信息你都储存在哪啊
Where do you store all this useless information?
无用  他单靠粗管短号就能上前十热曲榜
Useless? The man charted a top ten hit with a Flugelhorn.
-怎么样  比利  -1977年
- Status, Billy? - 1977.
拜托  我恨你
Please. I hate you.
"如此美好"  是吧
"Feels so good", doesn't it?
我来吧  斯蒂芬
I... I've got this, Stephen.
你该做的做完了  去吧  我们来缝合
You've done your bit. Go ahead, we'll close up.
-怎么了  -枪伤
- What is it? - GSW.
你居然还能保住他的命
It's amazing you kept him alive.
呼吸暂停  脑干测试
Apneic, failed the brain stem test...
和呼吸暂停反射测试均无反应
and the apnea reflex test.
我好像发现问题所在了  帕尔默医生
I think I found the problem, Dr. Palmer.
你把一颗子弹留在了他的脑子里
You left a bullet in his head.
谢谢  它撞到了髓质
Thanks. It's impinging on the medulla.
我需要专家意见  尼克已经判了脑死亡
I needed a specialist. Nic diagnose brain death.
但我就是觉得不对劲
Something about that doesn't feel right to me.
我们得跑了
We have to run.
韦斯特医生  你在做什么
Dr. West! What are you doing?
器官采集  他是捐献者
Organ harvest. He's a donor.
别急  我可没同意
Slow down. I did not agree to that.
我不需要你同意  我们已经判定脑死亡了
I don't need you to. We've already called brain death.
话说早了
Prematurely.
得为他准备进行枕下开颅手术
We need to get him prepped for sub-occipital craniotomy.
我不会让你给死人开刀的
Not gonna let you operate on a dead man.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
-一颗子弹  -一颗完好的子弹
- A bullet? - A perfect bullet.
子弹加固过
It's been hardened.
子弹加固是用铅锑合金
You harden a bullet by alloying lead with antimony.
有毒金属
A toxic metal.
而且子弹直接接触脑脊液
And that's leeched directly into the cerebral spinal fluid.
立刻造成中枢神经系统停摆
Rapid-onset central nervous system shutdown.
我们得走了
We got to go.
病人没死  但他要死了
The patient's not dead, but he's dying.
还要采集他的器官吗
Still want to harvest his organs?
我来协助你
I'll assist you.
不用  帕尔默医生会协助我的
No! Dr. Palmer will assist me.
谢谢
Thank you.
影像引导  立刻
Image guidance, stat.
没那个时间了
We don't have time for that.
你不能直接用手做
You can't do it freehand.
我能  我就要这么做
I can and I will.
这不是炫耀的时候  斯特兰奇
This isn't a time for showing off, Strange.
那十分钟前
How about ten minutes ago,
你错判了死亡时间时呢
when you called the wrong time of death?
颅神经未受损
Cranial nerves intact.
韦斯特医生  盖住你的表
Dr. West, cover your watch.
你没必要当着众人的面羞辱他的
You know, you didn't have to humiliate him in front of everyone.
我还没必要救他的病人呢  但是嘛...
I didn't have to save his patient, either. But, you know, I
我有时候就是忍不住
sometimes just can't help myself.
-尼克是个好医生  -你来找我了
- Nic is a great doctor. - You came to me.
我想听听别人的意见
Yeah, well, I needed a second opinion.
你已经听到了
You had a second opinion.
你想听到好的意见
What you needed was a competent one.
所以你更该当我的待命神经外科医生了
Well, all the more reason why you should be my neurosurgeon on call.
你可以做出很大贡献
You could make such a difference.
我不能在你的屠宰场工作
I can't work in your butcher shop.
我在做截断脊髓熔合术
Look, I'm fusing transected spinal cords.
以及刺激中枢神经的神经发生
I'm stimulating neurogenesis in the central nervous system.
我的工作在今后的年月里能拯救上千人
The work I'm doing is gonna save thousands for years to come.
而在急诊室  至多就是救拿枪的笨蛋醉鬼
In ER, you get to save one drunk idiot with a gun.
是啊  我们急诊室的人不过就是在救命
Yeah, you're right. In ER, we're only saving lives.
捞不到名声  没有CNN来采访
There's no fame, there's no CNN interviews...
那我只能继续用尼克了
Well, I guess I'll have to stick with Nic.
等等  你们不是...你俩没...
Oh, wait a minute. You're not... you guys aren't...
什么
What?
上床吧
Sleeping together.
抱歉  我以为我厌恶的口气能暗示我的意思了
Sorry, I thought that was implicit in my disgust.
其实非常明显
Explicit, actually.
没有  我有绝对不能跟同事约会的规矩
And no, I have a very strict rule against dating colleagues.
-是吗  -我称之为"斯特兰奇准则"
- Oh really? - I call it the Strange policy.
太棒了  很高兴有东西是以我命名的
Oh, good! I'm glad something's named after me.
我发明了一种椎板切除术手术
You know, I invented a laminectomy procedure,
但不知为何
and yet, somehow,
似乎没人愿意管它叫"斯特兰奇术"
no one seems to want to call it the Strange technique.
是我们一起发明了那个术式
We invented that technique.
不管怎样  你的准则让我受宠若惊
You know, regardless, I'm very flattered by your policy.
我...
Look, I'm...
我今晚要去参加个神经病学协会的晚宴
I'm talking tonight at a Neurological Society dinner.
一起来吧
Come with me.
又是去演讲  真浪漫
Another speaking engagement? So romantic.
你以前可喜欢跟我去参加这类活动了
You used to love coming to those things with me.
-我们很开心的  -不  是你很开心
- We had fun together. - No. You've had fun.
那不是以我们为主  是以你为主
They weren't about us, they were about you.
也不仅仅是我
Not only about me.
斯蒂芬  什么事都是以你为中心的
Stephen. Everything is about you.
或许可以用连字符
Maybe we could hyphenate.
斯特兰奇-帕尔默术
Strange-Palmer technique.
帕尔默-斯特兰奇术
Palmer-Strange.
比利  都有什么
Billy! What have you got for me?
35岁的空军上校
I've got a 35-year-old Air Force colonel.
穿实验性装甲压碎了下脊柱
Crushed his lower spine in some kind of experimental armor.
中胸廓爆裂骨折
Mid-thoracic burst fracture.
嗯  我是可以帮忙
Yeah, well, I could help,
但还有50个人也能帮他
but so could 50 other people.
给我找点值得做的
Find me something worth my time.
68岁女士  晚期脑干胶质细胞瘤
I have a 68-year-old female with an advanced brain stem glioma.
你是想让我破坏我的完美记录吗
Yeah, you want me to screw up my perfect record?
绝对不要
Definitely not.
22岁女性  脑内有电子植入物
How about a 22-year-old female with an electronic implant in her brain
以控制精神分裂症  却被闪电击中
to control schizophrenia struck by lightning?
这个听上去是很有趣
That does sound interesting.
能不能发给我...
Can you send me the...
收到了
got it.
没事的  不会有事的
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
他们做了什么
What did they do?
他们用直升机送你过来的
They rushed you in a chopper.
但找到你费了不少时间
But it took a little while to find you.
你在车里时  修复神经损伤的黄金时期就过去了
The golden hours for nerve damage went by while you were in the car.
他们做了什么
What did they do?!
11根不锈钢针插入骨头
11 stainless steel pins in the bones.
多处韧带撕裂
Multiple torn ligaments.
双手严重神经损伤
Severe nerve damage in both hands.
你在手术台上躺了11个小时
You were on the table for 11 hours.
看看这些固定器
Look at these fixators.
没人能做得更好了
No one could have done better.
我就能做得更好
I could have done better.
不
No.
给你的身体点时间愈合
Give your body time to heal.
你毁了我
You've ruined me.
我还要多久才能...
How long until I can tak...
斯特兰奇医生  你的组织还在愈合
Dr. Strange... those tissues are still healing.
那就加快速度
So speed it up.
把支架沿肱动脉伸入桡动脉下
Pass a stent down the brachial artery into the radial artery.
可能可行
It's possible.
是昂贵的实验性疗法  但有可能
Experimental and expensive, but possible.
有可能就行
All I need is possible.
张开
Up.
拿出点力气来
Show me your strength.
这根本没用
This is useless.
不是没用的  你可以的
It's not useless, man, you can do this.
那回答我  学士
All right, answer me this, bachelor's degree.
你见过谁遭受了这么严重的神经损伤
Have you ever known anyone with nerve damage this severe
经过理疗  康复了吗
to do this, and actually recover?
有一个人
One guy, yeah.
工厂事故  脊椎断了  瘫痪了
Factory accident, broke his back. Paralyzed.
他的腿日渐萎缩
His leg wasted away.
因为推轮椅  他肩膀疼
He had pain in his shoulder from the wheelchair.
他一周来三次
He came in 3 times a week.
有一天  突然不来了  我以为他死了
And then one day stopped coming. I thought he was dead.
几年后  他在街上从我身边走过
A few years later, he walked past me on the street.
-走  -对  走
- Walked? - Yeah, walked.
扯淡  拿他的病例给我
Bullshit. Show me his file.
从档案馆里找到他的病例得要点时间
It'll take me a while to pull the files from the archive.
但如果能证明你个自大鬼错了
But if it proves your arrogant ass wrong,
那也值了
worth it.
我看过了你所有的研究
I looked at all your research.
读了你发来的所有论文  这是行不通的
I read all the papers you've sent, it's no gonna work.
我觉得你并不明白  你伤得多重
I... I don't think you realize how severe the damages are...
-是这样的  -最优秀的医生都没能做到
- Look, here's the thing, I... - The best have tried and failed.
我理解  是这样的
Look, I understand. Here's the thing. I...
你要我做的事根本不可能  斯蒂芬
What you want from me is impossible, Stephen.
拜托
Come on...
-我还得考虑自己的名声  -拜托
- I've got my own reputation to consider. - Come on.
埃蒂安  等等
Etienne, wait.
-我没法帮你  -等等  别
- I can't help you... - Wait. No.
不不  等等
No, no, wait!
他不肯做
He won't do it.
他是个庸医
He's a hack.
东京有种新手术
There is a new procedure in Tokyo.
他们培养捐献者的干细胞
They culture donor stem cells and then
进行采集  然后3D打印个支架
harvesting them and 3D-printing a scaffold.
如果我能借到钱
If I could get a loan together, just...
-斯蒂芬  斯蒂芬  -一小笔  20万
- Stephen... Stephen. - A small loan, 200,000.
你一直是挣多少花多少
You've always spent money as fast as you could make it
但你现在是在花你没有的钱
but now you're spending money you don't even have.
或许该考虑停止了
Maybe it's time to consider stopping.
不  现在才更不能停止
No. Now is exactly the time not to stop.
因为  我并没有好转
Because, you see, I'm not getting any better!
但这已经不是求医了  这是发疯
But this isn't medicine anymore. This is mania.
有些东西就是治不好
Some things just can't be fixed.
-没有工作的生活  -也还是生活
- Life without my work... - Is still life.
这不是末路
This isn't the end.
还有其他事能让你的生命富有意义
There are other things that can give your life meaning.
什么  你吗
Like what? Like you?
你现在该道歉了
And this is the part where you apologize.
你现在该走了
This is the part where you leave.
好吧  我也看不下去你再这么折磨自己了
Fine. I can't watch you do this to yourself anymore.
-太艰难了  是吗  -没错
- Too difficult for you, is it? - Yes.
是的
It is.
看到你这样令我心碎
It breaks my heart to see you this way.
不  别可怜我
No. Don't pity me.
我不是在可怜你
I'm not pitying you.
是吗  那你为什么来
Oh yeah? Then what are you doing here?
带奶酪和酒来
Bringing cheese and wine
好像我们是去吃野餐的老朋友
like we're old friends going for a picnic?
我们不是朋友  克里斯汀
We are not friends, Christine.
我们连情人都算不上
We were barely lovers.
你就喜欢悲剧故事  是吧
But you just love a sob story, don't you?
你现在就这么看我了吗
Is that what I am to you now?
可怜的斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇  施舍对象
Poor Stephen Strange, charity case.
他终于需要我了
He finally needs me.
又一个你可以拯救的人性渣滓
Another dreg of humanity for you to work on.
把他包扎好  让他重新回归社会
Patch him up and send him back into the world,
心里简直要唱起歌
hearts just humming...
你非常在乎  是吧
You care so much! Don't you?!
再见  斯蒂芬
Goodbye, Stephen.
斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇
我说的吧
乔·潘伯恩
拜托  拿出点真本事来啊
Come on, man! Where is the competition?
你话真多
Talk a lot!
乔纳森·潘伯恩  C7-C8脊椎完全性损伤
Jonathan Pangborn, C7-C8 spinal cord injury, complete.
-你是谁  -胸部以下瘫痪
- Who are you? - Paralyzed from the mid-chest down.
双手部分瘫痪
Partial paralysis in both hands.
我不认识你
I don't know you.
我是斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇
I'm Stephen Strange.
是个神经外科医生  曾经是
I'm a neurosurgeon. Was a neurosurgeon.
你知道吗  我还真认识你
Actually, you know what, man? I do know you.
我曾经去过你办公室  你拒绝见我
I came to your office once. You refused to see me.
我连你助理那关都没过
I never got past your assistant.
你当时没法医治
You were untreatable.
治不好就得不到荣誉  是吧
No glory for you in that, right?
你从万劫不复的病情中康复了
You came back from a place there's no way back from!
我也想找到我的康复之路
I'm trying to find my own way back.
潘伯恩  你还打不打了
Pangborn, are you in or you out?
好吧
All right.
我本来都放弃我的身体了
I'd given up on my body.
我以为我只剩下思维了
I thought my mind's the only thing I had left.
至少也该努力提升它一下
I should at least try to elevate that.
所以我去见大师
So I sat with gurus,
还有圣女
and sacred women.
陌生人抬着我上山顶去见圣人
Strangers carried me to mountain tops to see holy men.
最终  我找到了我的导师
And finally, I found my teacher.
我的思维得到了提升
And my mind was elevated.
灵魂得到了深化
And my spirit deepened.
-不知如何  -你的身体痊愈了
- And somehow... - Your body healed.
是啊
Yes.
还有更深奥的秘密等着我学习
And there were deeper secrets to learn there,
但我没有体力去接受了
but I didn't have the strength to receive them.
我安于我的奇迹  回家来了
I chose to settle for my miracle, and I came back home.
你找的地方叫卡马塔奇
The place you're looking for is called Kamar-Taj.
-但那里代价[价格]很高  -多少钱
- But the cost there is high. - How much?
我指的不是钱
I'm not talking about money.
祝你好运
Good luck.
玩球吧  来啊
Let's ball. All right, ball up!
尼泊尔  加德满都
不好意思  打扰一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
卡马塔奇
Kamar-Taj?
你知道卡马塔奇在哪吗
You know where Kamar-Taj is?
找到安宁  找到自己
卡马塔奇
Kamar-Taj?
Kamar-Taj...
好吧
Okay.
伙计们  我没有钱
Look guys, I... I don't have any money.
你的手表
Your watch.
不  求你们了
No, please.
-我只剩这个了  -你的手表
- It's all I have left. - Your watch.
好吧
All right.
你在找卡马塔奇
You're looking for Kamar-Taj?
真的吗
Really?
你确定找对地方了吗
Sure you got the right place?
那里看起来更...
That one looks a little more...
卡马塔奇一些
Kamar Taj-y.
我曾经和你一样
I once stood in your place.
我也曾经...
And I, too, was...
很不敬
disrespectful.
我给你点建议
So might I offer you some advice?
忘掉你自以为知道的一切
Forget everything you think you know.
好吧
All right.
这圣殿属于我们的导师
The sanctuary of our teacher.
古一法师
The Ancient One.
古一法师  他真名叫什么
The Ancient One? What's his real name?
对了  忘掉我自以为知道的一切  抱歉
Right. Forget everything I think I know. Sorry.
感谢你...
Thank you for...
好吧  这是...规矩吗
Okay, that's, uh... a thing...
谢谢
Thank you for...
你好
Hello.
谢谢
Uh, thank you.
也谢谢你
And thank you.
感谢你  古一法师  愿意见我
Uh, thank you, Ancient One... for... seeing me...
不客气
You're very welcome.
-古一法师  -谢谢  莫多法师
- The Ancient One. - Thank you, Master Mordo.
谢谢  哈密尔法师
Thank you, Master Hamir!
斯特兰奇先生
Mr. Strange!
其实是博士
Doctor, actually.
肯定不再是了
Well, no. Not anymore, surely.
你不正是因此而来的吗
Isn't that why you're here?
你做了许多次手术
You've undergone many procedures.
-七次  对吧  -对
- Seven, right? - Yeah...
-好茶  -是啊
- It's good tea. - Yes.
你是不是治好了一个叫潘伯恩的人  他瘫痪了
Did you heal a man named Pangborn? A paralyzed man.
算是吧
In a way.
你帮了他  他又能走了
You helped him to walk again.
对
Yes.
你是怎么治好C7-C8脊椎完全性损伤的
How did you correct a complete C7-C8 spinal cord injury?
不是治好了
I didn't correct it.
他不能走  我让他相信他能
He couldn't walk; I convinced him that he could.
你不是指身心治疗吧
You're not suggesting it was psychosomatic?
你把断掉的神经接好后
When you reattach a severed nerve,
是你  还是身体让它痊愈
is it you who heals it back together or the body?
-是细胞  -而细胞被设定好
- It's the cells. - And the cells are only programmed
以特定的方式来痊愈
to put themselves back together in very specific ways.
对
Right.
如果我告诉你  你可以说服身体相信
What if I told you that your own body could be convinced
它能以各种各样的方式痊愈呢
to put itself back together in all sorts of ways?
你是说细胞再生
You're talking about cellular regeneration.
这种技术非常尖端
That's... bleeding-edge medical tech.
所以你才在这里工作吗
Is that why you're working here,
脱离医院董事会的监管
without a governing medical board? I mean...
你的治疗方法实验性多强
just how experimental is your treatment?
非常强
Quite.
所以  你有办法让神经细胞重组自愈吗
So, you've figured out a way to reprogram nerve cells to self-heal?
不  斯特兰奇先生
No, Mr. Strange.
我知道如何调整精神力量  使身体更好地愈合
I know how to reorient the spirit to better heal the body.
精神力量...愈合身体
The spirit... to heal the body.
没错
That's right.
好吧
No. Al... Al... All right.
我们要怎么做  从哪开始
How do we do that? Where do we start?
不喜欢那张图吗
Don't like that map?
不是的  它真的很不错
Oh, no. It's... it's really good.
只是...我以前见过这个
It's just... you know, I've seen it before.
在礼品店里
In gift shops.
那这张呢
And what about this one?
-针灸  厉害  -是吧
- Acupuncture, great. - Yeah?
那张怎么样
What about... that one?
你是在给我看核磁共振图吗  难以置信
Showing me an MRI scan? I do not believe this.
画每张图的人  都只能窥视局部
Each of those maps was drawn up by someone who could see in part,
而看不到全局
but not the whole.
我为来这儿  花了最后的一点钱
I spent my last dollar getting here
买了张单程票
one-way ticket,
你却在跟我说信仰治疗
and you're talking to me about healing through belief?
你是一个通过钥匙孔窥视世界的人
You're a man looking at the world through a keyhole,
你这一生  都在试图扩大那个钥匙孔
you've spent your whole life trying to widen that keyhole.
想看到更多  知道更多
To see more, to know more.
而如今听闻  这钥匙孔可以扩大
And now, on hearing that it can be widen
是以你无法想象的方式  你却抗拒这个可能性吗
in ways you can't imagine, you reject the possibility?
不  我拒绝是因为我不信天方夜谭
No, I reject it because I do not believe in fairy tales
什么脉轮  能量  信仰的力量
about chakras, or energy, or the power of belief.
根本没有精神力量这东西
There is no such thing as spirit!
我们都由物质构成  别无他物
We are made of matter, and nothing more.
你只是一粒小小的  转瞬即逝的尘埃
You're just another tiny, momentary speck
漂浮在这冷漠的世界里
within an indifferent universe.
你太妄自菲薄了
You think too little of yourself.
你自以为能看穿我  是吗
You think you see through me, do you?
你才不能呢
Well, you don't.
我倒是看穿你了
But I see through you!!
你刚对我做了什么
What did you just do to me?!
我将你的魂体打出了你的肉体
I pushed your astral form out of your physical form.
那杯茶里加了什么
What's in that tea?
裸头草碱[迷幻药]  还是迷幻剂
Psilocybin? LSD?
就是茶
It's just tea.
加了一点蜂蜜
With a little honey.
刚发生了什么
What just happened?
那一瞬间  你进入了精神次元
For a moment, you entered the astral dimension.
-什么  -魂魄与躯壳不共生的地方
- The what? - A place where the soul exists apart from the body.
你为什么要这样对我
Why are you doing this to me?
为了让你明白你有多无知
To show you just how much you don't know.
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eye.
该死
Shit!
上帝啊  上帝啊
Oh god! Oh god!
不不不不不
No. No. No. No. No. No.
怎么回事
What's happening?
这不是真的  不是真的
This isn't real. This isn't real.
不是真的  这是...
This isn't real. This is...
上帝啊
Oh god!
不不不不不
No. No. No. No. No. No.
他的心率太高  有点危险
His heart rate is getting dangerously high.
我看他挺好的
He looks all right to me.
你自以为明白这世界如何运转
You think you know how the world works?
你以为这物质宇宙就是全部了吗
You think that this material universe is all there is?
何为真实
What is real?
你感官无法触及之处  还有怎样的奥秘
What mysteries lie beyond the reach of your senses?
在万物存在的根源处  思维与物质交合
At the root of existence, mind and matter meet.
思维塑造现实
Thoughts shape reality.
这个宇宙不过无数个宇宙之一
This universe is only one of an infinite number.
无尽的世界
Worlds without end.
有些世界充满仁爱与生命
Some benevolent and life-giving;
有些则满是恶念与饥荒
Others filled with malice and hunger.
还有黑暗之地  存在着比时间更古老的力量
Dark places, where powers older than time lie...
贪婪地
ravenous...
等待着
and waiting.
在浩瀚的多元宇宙间  你是谁
Who are you in this vast multiverse,
斯特兰奇先生
Mr. Strange?
你在礼品店见过这个吗
Have you seen that before in a gift shop?
教教我
Teach me!
不
No.
不...
No...
不要
No!
不不不不  不要
No, no, no, no no no no!
不要  开门  求你了
No! Open the door! Please!
谢谢  各位法师
Thank you, Masters.
你觉得我不该赶他走吗
You think I was wrong to cast him out?
五小时了  他还在你门口
5 hours later, he's still on your doorstep.
他身上有股力量
There's a strength to him.
顽固  自负  野心...我都见过
Stubbornness, arrogance, ambition... I've seen it all before.
他让你想起了卡西利亚斯吗
He reminds you of Kaecilius?
我不能再教另一个天赋异禀的学生学会强大法术
I cannot lead another gifted student to power,
再看着他被黑暗吞噬
only to lose him to the darkness.
我就没有那样
You didn't lose me.
我想获得力量  打败敌人
I wanted the power to defeat my enemies.
你给了我力量打败心魔
You gave me the power to defeat my demons.
并遵守自然法则
And to live within the natural law.
我们永远不能摆脱心魔  莫多
We never lose our demons, Mordo.
我们只能学会抑制它们
We only learn to live above them.
被偷的几页书还在卡西利亚斯手上
Kaecilius still has the stolen pages.
如果他成功破解  就能毁灭我们所有人
If he deciphers them, he could bring ruin upon us all.
黑暗的日子可能就要到来
There may be dark days ahead.
卡马塔奇或许用得上斯特兰奇这样的人
Perhaps Kamar-Taj could use a man like Strange.
别把我挡在外面
Don't shut me out.
我没别的地方可去了
I haven't got anywhere else to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
洗澡
Bathe.
休息
Rest.
或是冥想
Meditate...
如果你可以的话
if you can.
古一法师会派人来找你的
The Ancient One will send for you.
这是什么  我的咒语吗
What's this? My mantra?
是无线网密码
The Wi-Fi password.
我们又不是野蛮人
We're not savages.
时间会表明
我爱你多深
~
克里斯汀
魔法的语言和人类文明一样古老
The language of the mystic arts is as old as civilization.
古代的法师
The sorcerers of antiquity
把这种语言的使用称为"咒语"
called the use of this language "Spells".
但如果这个词有违你的现代思维
But if that word offends your modern sensibilities,
你可以把它称作"程序"
you can call it a "Program".
它是塑造了现实的源代码
The source code that shapes reality.
我们汲取能量
We harness energy
来自多元宇宙其他次元的能量
drawn from other dimensions of the multiverse,
来施咒
to cast spells,
变出护盾
to conjure shields
和武器
and weapons
创造魔法
to make magic.
但是
But...
即使我的手指可以做到
even if my fingers could do that,
我的手也只是在胡乱挥舞而已
my hands would just be waving in the air. I mean,
我怎么才能达到你那种程度呢
how do I get from here to there?
那你是如何能连接断裂的神经
How did you get to reattach severed nerves, and
一节一节地修复人的脊椎呢
put a human spine back together bone by bone?
多年的学习和练习
Study and practice. Years of it.
-斯特兰奇先生  -叫我斯蒂芬就好
- Mr. Strange. - Stephen, please.
-那你是  -王
- And you are? - Wong.
王
Wong.
就单一个王吗
Just Wong?
就像  阿黛尔
Like... Adele?
或者  亚里士多德
Or... Aristotle.
德雷克
Drake.
博诺
Bono.
阿姆
Eminem.
《幻日之书》
The Book of the Invisible Sun.
《新天文学》
Astronomia Nova.
《统御法典》
Codex Imperium.
《所罗门钥匙》
Key of Solomon.
-你全都看完了吗  -对
- You finished all of this? - Yup.
-跟我来  -好
- Come with me. - All right.
这个区域仅对法师开放
This section is for Masters only.
但如果有我的允许  其他人也可以看
But at my discretion, others may use it.
从《马克西姆的启蒙》开始看吧
We should start with Maxim's Primer.
你的梵文怎么样
How's your Sanskrit?
我谷歌翻译用得挺溜
I'm fluent in Google Translate.
吠陀  古典梵语
Vedic, classical Sanskrit.
那些是什么
What are those?
古一法师的私人收藏
The Ancient One's private collection.
所以禁止阅览吗
So they're forbidden?
卡马塔奇没有禁止阅览的知识
No knowledge in Kamar-Taj is forbidden.
只有个别禁施的法术
Only certain practices.
除了至尊法师
Those books are far too advanced
那些书对其他人来说太过深奥
for anyone other than the Sorcerer Supreme.
这本书有缺页
This one's got pages missing.
那是《卡里奥斯特罗之书》  是研究时间的
That's the Book of Cagliostro. A study of time.
一个前法师偷走了一个法事
One of the rituals was stolen by a former Master.
是个狂热信徒  叫卡西利亚斯
The zealot, Kaecilius.
他还把前任图书管理员吊了起来
Just after he strung up the former librarian,
并砍下了他的首级
and relieved him of his head.
现在我来守卫这些书
I am now the guardian of these books.
所以如果再有一本藏书被偷
So if a volume from this collection should be stolen again,
我都会知道
I'd know it.
你还不及离开这里就会没命
And you'd be dead before you ever left the compound.
那如果只是逾期了呢
What if it's just overdue? You know?
会有什么逾期费吗  打个伤残什么的
Any... late fees I should know about? Maiming, perhaps.
知道吗  以前大家都觉得我很幽默呢
You know, people used to think that I was funny.
他们是你的手下吗
Did they work for you?
好吧  跟你谈话真愉快
All right. Well, it's been lovely talking to you,
谢谢你给我找书  给我讲恐怖故事
thank you for the books and for the horrifying story and
并对我进行人身威胁
for the threat upon my life.
现在我们将得到力量消灭背叛我们的人
We will now receive the power to destroy the one who betrayed us.
也是背叛世界的人
The one who betrays the world.
掌握悬戒是学习魔法必不可少的
Mastery of the sling ring is essential to the mystic arts.
悬戒让我们可以在多元宇宙中穿行
They allow us to travel throughout the multiverse.
你所要做的就是集中精神
All you need to do is focus.
去想象
Visualize.
在脑海中勾勒出目的地
See the destination in your mind.
目光超越你面前的世界
Look beyond the world in front of you.
想象出每个细节
Imagine every detail.
画面越清晰  召唤传送门就会
The clearer the picture, the quicker, and easier,
越快  越容易
the gateway will come.
停下
And stop.
我想和斯特兰奇先生单独谈谈
I would like a moment alone with Mr. Strange.
没问题
Of course.
-都怪我的手  -这和你的手无关
- My hands. - It's not about your hands.
这怎么会和我的手无关
How is this not about my hands?
哈密尔法师
Master Hamir.
有劳了  哈密尔法师
Thank you, Master Hamir.
你无法打得河流服从你
You cannot beat a river into submission.
你得顺应它的流势
You have to surrender to its current,
化其力量为己用
and use its power as your own.
我要放弃掌控  才能掌控它吗
I... I control it by surrendering control?
那根本没道理啊
That doesn't make any sense.
并非凡事都有道理  也并非都必须有道理
Not everything does. Not everything has to.
你的智力引领了你的人生
Your intellect has taken you far in life.
但它不会让你更进一步了
But it will take you no further.
顺从吧  斯蒂芬
Surrender, Stephen.
放下你的自负
Silence your ego
你的力量才会显现
and your power will rise.
跟我来
Come with me.
-等等  这是不是...  -珠穆朗玛峰
- Wait. Is this... - Everest.
-真美  -没错
- Beautiful. - Yeah, right.
很美  很冷  但...很美
Beautiful. Freezing, but... beautiful.
在这种温度下  人只能存活30分钟
At this temperature, a person can last for 30 minutes
-然后就会永久丧失身体机能  -太好了
- before suffering permanent loss of function. - Great.
但前两分钟内你大概就会休克
But you'll likely go into shock within the first 2.
什么
What?
-顺从吧  斯蒂芬  -不不  不要
- Surrender, Stephen. - No, no!!! Don't!
-新来的怎么样了  -即将见分晓
- How's our new recruit? - We shall see.
随时了
Any second now.
不会吧  又来
No, not again.
或许我该...
Maybe I should...
-斯蒂芬  -王
- Stephen. - Wong.
-你要什么  斯特兰奇  -魂体投射的书
- What do you want, Strange? - Books on astral projection.
-你还没准备好  -放马过来  碧昂斯
- You're not ready for that. - Try me, Beyonce.
得了  你听说过她吧  她可是大腕啊
Come on. You've heard of her. She's a huge star, right?
你笑过吗
Do you ever laugh?
得了  把书给我吧
Come on, just give me the book.
不行
No.
就在这个房间  你曾求我教你
Once, in this room, you begged me to let you learn.
如今我却听说  你质疑所有教导
Now I'm told you question every lesson,
而更喜欢自学
prefering to teach yourself.
就在这个房间  你曾要我睁开眼睛
Once, in this room, you told me to open my eyes.
如今我却听说  要盲目遵守毫无道理的规矩
Now I'm being told to blindly accept rules that make no sense.
比如不能在图书馆里开传送门吗
Like the rule against conjuring a gateway in the library?
王打我小报告
Wong told on me?
你的魔法法术进步很快
You're advancing quickly with your sorcery skills.
你需要一个安全的地方练习咒语
You need a safe space to practice your spells.
你现在处于镜像次元中
You are now inside the Mirror Dimension.
永恒存在但不会被发觉
Ever present but undetected.
这里的事不会影响真实世界
The real world isn't affected by what happens here.
我们在镜像次元中训练  监视
We use the Mirror Dimension to train, surveil,
也会用它来控制威胁
and sometimes to contain threats.
千万不要没戴悬戒被困在这里
You don't wanna be stuck in here without your sling ring.
等等  抱歉  你刚说的威胁是什么意思
Hold on. Sorry, what do you mean, threats?
了解无穷的多元宇宙
Learning of an infinite multiverse
就也要了解无尽的危险
includes learning of infinite dangers.
如果我把所有你尚不知道的东西都告诉你
And if I told you everything else that you don't already know,
你只会仓皇逃跑
you'd run from here in terror.
话说  她究竟有多老
So, just how ancient is she?
没人知道至尊法师的年龄
No one knows the age of the Sorcerer Supreme.
只知道她是凯尔特人  从不提起往事
Only that she is Celtic and never talks about her past.
你不了解她还追随她
You follow her even though you don't know?
我知道她坚定不移  却又高深莫测
I know that she's steadfast, but unpredictable.
无情  却有仁爱之心
Merciless, yet kind.
是她成就了如今的我
She made me what I am.
相信你的导师
Trust your teacher.
切勿迷失方向
And don't lose your way.
-像卡西利亚斯那样吗  -对
- Like Kaecilius? - That's right.
你认识他
You knew him.
他刚来时  失去了所有挚爱之人
When he first came to us, he'd lost everyone he ever loved.
他悲痛欲绝
He was a grieving, broken man,
在魔法中寻找答案
searching for answers in the mystic arts.
他是个才华横溢的学生  但自傲又顽固
A brilliant student, but he was proud, headstrong.
他质疑古一法师  排斥我们的教导
He questioned the Ancient One, rejected our teaching.
他离开了卡马塔奇
He left Kamar-Taj.
他的门徒如羊群般跟随
His disciples followed him like sheep
被伪教义迷惑
seduced by false doctrine.
-他偷了一个禁忌法事  对吗  -对
- He stole the forbidden ritual, right? - Yes.
那是干什么的
What did it do?
别再问问题了
No more questions.
-那是什么  -这也是问题
- What's that? - That's a question.
这是个法器
This is a relic.
有些魔法太过强大  无法维持
Some magic is too powerful to sustain,
我们唯有将其注入物件之中
so we imbue objects with it.
让它们去承受我们承受不了的负担
Allowing them to take the strain we can not.
这
This
就是生命法庭权杖
is the Staff of the Living Tribunal.
有很多法器
There are many relics.
瓦图姆魔杖
The Wand of Watoomb.
佛多之靴
The Vaulting Boots of Valtorr.
真是朗朗上口  对吧
Really just roll off the tongue, don't they?
我什么时候能有自己的法器
When do I get my relic?
-等你准备好  -我觉得我准备好了
- When you're ready. - I think I'm ready.
法器觉得你准备好了  你才算准备好了
You're ready when the relic decides you're ready.
现在
For now,
变出一个武器来吧
conjure a weapon.
好吧
All right.
战斗
Fight!
就好像你命系于此
Fight like your life depended on it!
因为有一天  或许真会如此
Because one day, it may.
克里斯汀
我再给你发一次邮件
王
Wong?
好了
Okay.
首先  打开阿戈摩托之眼
First, open the Eye of Agamotto.
好吧
All right.
我的天
Oh my.
能不能...
What if...
多玛姆
Dormammu.
黑暗次元
The Dark Dimension.
永生
Eternal life?
怎么...
What the...
停下
Stop!!!
干涉时空连续性是大忌
Tampering with continuum probabilitie is forbidden!
我只是...在照书上的指示操作
I... I wa... I was just doing exactly what it said in the book!
那进行法事的危险
And what did the book say
书上是怎么说的呢
about the dangers of performing that ritual?
我不知道  我还没看到那儿
I don't know. I hadn't gotten to that part yet.
操纵时间会创建出时间分支
Temporal manipulations can create branches in time.
不稳定的次元开口
Unstable dimensional openings.
空间悖论  时间循环
Spatial paradoxes! Time loops!!!
你想被困在一遍遍重复的时间段里吗
You wanna get stuck reliving the same moment over, and over, forever,
或是存在完全被抹去
or never having existed at all?
警告真的应该放在咒语前
Really should put the warnings before the spell.
你的好奇心可能会害死你
Your curiosity could have gotten you killed.
你不是在操纵时空连续性
You weren't manipulating the space-time continuum,
而是在破坏它
you were breaking it.
我们不打破自然法则
We do not tamper with natural law.
而是保卫它
We defend it.
你怎么做到的
How did you even do that?
你从哪学到的理解它所需要的
Where did you learn the litany of spells required
冗长的咒语
to even understand it?
我过目不忘
I've got a photographic memory.
所以才能同时拿到医学和哲学博士学位
That's how I got my M.D. and Ph.D. at the same time.
你刚刚做到的
What you just did
需要的不仅是好记性
takes more than a good memory.
你就是为魔法而生的
You were born for the mystic arts.
-但我的手还在抖  -暂时还在抖
- And yet, my hands still shake. - For now, yes.
-不会永远如此吗  -我们不是先知
- Not forever? - We're not prophets.
你们什么时候才肯告诉我  我们是什么
When are you gonna start telling me what we are?
复仇者那样的英雄
While heroes like the Avengers
保护世界免受实体伤害
protect the world from physical dangers,
而我们法师捍卫世界  抵御魔法威胁
we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.
古一法师是最新一位继承了至尊法师头衔的人
The Ancient One is the latest in a long line of Sorcerers Supreme.
他们可追溯至千百年前的魔法鼻祖
Going back thousands of years to the father of the mystic arts,
全能的阿戈摩托
the mighty Agamotto.
就是那个创造了被你鲁莽借用的魔眼法器的法师
Same sorcerer who created the eye you so recklessly borrowed.
阿戈摩托在魔力强的地方造了三座圣殿
Agamotto built 3 Sanctums in places of power,
这些地方如今都是大城市
where great cities now stand.
那扇门通往香港圣殿
That door leads to the Hong Kong Sanctum,
那扇通往纽约圣殿
that door to the New York Sanctum.
那扇通往伦敦圣殿
That one, to the London Sanctum.
三座圣殿一起
Together, the Sanctums
生成了一面保护世界的盾牌
generate a protective shield around our world.
圣殿保护世界
The Sanctums protect the world,
我们法师保护圣殿
and we sorcerers protect the Sanctums.
抵御什么
From what?
其他次元里威胁我们宇宙的存在
Other-dimensional beings that threaten our universe.
比如多玛姆
Like Dormammu?
你从哪知道的这个名字
Where did you learn that name?
我刚在《卡里奥斯特罗之书》里读到的  怎么了
I just read it in the book of Cagliostro. Why?
多玛姆存在于黑暗次元中
Dormammu dwells in the Dark Dimension.
超越时间
Beyond time.
他是宇宙征服者  世界摧毁者
He is the cosmic conquerer, the destroyer of worlds.
拥有无尽力量和无限渴望
A being of infinite power and endless hunger,
他想要侵略所有宇宙
on a quest to invade every universe
把所有世界都纳入他的黑暗次元
and bring all worlds into his Dark Dimension.
他最渴望地球
And he hungers for Earth most of all.
卡西利亚斯偷的那几页
The pages that Kaecilius stole.
一种联系多玛姆
A ritual to contact Dormammu
并从黑暗次元中汲取能量的法事
and draw power from the Dark Dimension.
好吧
Okay.
我退出  我...
I'm out. I...
我是来治手的
I came here to heal my hands,
不是来打什么魔法战争
not to fight in some mystical war.
伦敦
London.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius!
不
No!!!
王  莫多
Wong? Mordo?
布里克街117A
有人吗
Hello?
丹尼尔
Daniel.
他们任命你为这座圣殿的法师了啊
I see they made you Master of this Sanctum.
你知道那意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
你会为保护它而死
That you'll die protecting it.
住手
Stop!
你到卡马塔奇多久了  你叫...
How long have you been at Kamar-Taj, Mister...?
是博士
Doctor.
-博士先生  -我姓斯特兰奇[是挺怪]
- Mr Doctor? - It's Strange.
也许吧
Maybe.
这又不由我来说
Who am I to judge?
你不知道怎么用  是吧
You don't know how to use that, do you?
什么
What?
别说了
Stop it.
叫你别说了
I said, stop it!
你阻止不了它的  博士先生
You cannot stop this, Mr. Doctor.
听着  我都不知道"它"是什么
Why... look, I don't even know what "This" is.
它既是开始也是结束
It's the end and the beginning.
多数人变成少数人  变成唯一
The many becoming the few, becoming the One.
你要是不想说明白
Look, if you're not gonna start making sense,
我就再给你戴上它
I'm just gonna have to put this thing back on.
告诉我  博士先生
Tell me, Mr. Doctor.
听着  我叫斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇博士
All right, look. My name is Dr. Stephen Strange.
-你是博士  -对
- You are a doctor? - Yeah.
科学家
A scientist.
你懂自然规律
You understand the laws of nature.
一切事物都会变老死去
All things age. All things die.
最终  太阳将燃尽
In the end, our sun burns out,
我们的宇宙将变冷毁灭
our universe grows cold and perishes.
但黑暗次元
But the Dark Dimension...
那个地方超越了时间
it's a place beyond time.
够了  我再给你戴上
That's it. I'm putting this thing back on.
这个世界不非得灭亡  博士
This world doesn't have to die, Doctor.
这个世界有权和其他很多世界一样
This world can take its rightful place alongside so many others,
成为唯一的一部分
as part of the One.
伟大而美丽的唯一
The great and beautiful One.
我们都能永生
And we can all live forever.
是嘛
Really?
这个新时代乌托邦次元对你有什么好处
What do you have to gain out of this New Age dimensional utopia?
跟你  跟所有人一样
The same as you. The same as everyone.
生命  永恒的生命
Life. Eternal life.
人们总是从善恶角度思考
People think in terms of good and evil,
但其实时间才是所有人真正的敌人
when really, time is the true enemy of us all.
时间会杀死一切
Time kills everything.
那你杀死的人呢
What about the people you killed?
那都只是微小  转瞬即逝的尘埃
Tiny, momentary specks
漂浮在这冷漠的世界里
within an indifferent universe.
是的  你明白了吧
Yes. You see,
你明白我们在做什么了吧
you see what we're doing?
这世界不是它应该有的样子
The world is not what it ought to be.
人类渴望永恒
Humanity longs for the eternal,
渴望超越时间的世界  因为时间奴役我们
for a world beyond time, because time is what enslaves us.
时间是一种侮辱
Time is an insult.
死亡是一种侮辱
Death is an insult.
博士
Doctor...
我们不求统治世界
We don't seek to rule this world.
我们求的是拯救它  把它交给多玛姆
We seek to save it, to hand it over to Dormammu,
他才是一切进化的目的
who is the intent of all evolution,
才是一切生命存在的缘由
the Why of all existence.
至尊法师保卫生命
The Sorcerer Supreme defends existence.
是什么让你前往卡马塔奇  博士
What was it that brought you to Kamar-Taj, Doctor?
是教化
Was it enlightenment?
还是力量
Power?
你是想去被治愈  我们都是
You came to be healed, as did we all.
卡马塔奇吸纳了各种残破的东西
Kamar-Taj is a place that collects broken things.
我们都是为治愈的希望而来
We all come with the promise of being healed,
但结果  古一只教我们些雕虫小技
and instead, the Ancient One gives us parlor tricks.
真正的魔法被她据为己有
The real magic she keeps for herself.
你就没想过她是怎么活得这么久的吗
You ever wondered how she managed to live this long?
我在《卡里奥斯特罗之书》中看到了那些法事
I saw the rituals in the book of Cagliostro.
看来你知道
So, you know.
法事给了我
The ritual gives me the power
打倒古一  拆毁圣殿的力量
to overthrow the Ancient One and tear her Sanctums down,
好让黑暗次元进来
to let the Dark Dimension in.
因为古一私藏的  多玛姆会无私给予
Because what the Ancient One hoards, Dormammu gives freely.
生命  永生
Life, everlasting.
他不是世界的毁灭者  博士
He is not the destroyer of worlds, Doctor,
而是世界的拯救者
he is the savior of worlds.
不  拜托  看看你的脸
No. I mean, come on. Look at your face.
多玛姆把你变成了凶手
Dormammu made you a murderer.
他的王国又能好到哪去
Just how good can his kingdom be?
你觉得这很有趣
You think that's funny?
不是因为那个
No. Not that.
有趣的是  你的悬戒丢了
What's funny is that you've lost your sling ring.
先生  要帮忙吗
Sir, can I help you?
帕尔默医生  她在哪
Dr. Palmer, where is she?
-先生  我们得...  -她在哪
- Sir, we need to get... - Where is she?
在护士站
The nurses station.
克里斯汀
Christine!
斯蒂芬
Stephen?
天啊  怎么
Oh my god. What...
你得马上带我找个手术室  就你一个人
You need to get me in an operating theater now. Just you.
快  我没时间了
Now! I haven't any time!
-怎么了  -被刺了
- What happened? - I was stabbed.
心脏填塞
Cardiac tamponade.
你穿的是什么
What are you wearing?
胸腔没问题
Chest cavity is clear.
不  血液  积在围心囊
No, the blood... is in the pericardial sac.
不不不
No. No no no no no no no!
斯蒂芬  斯蒂芬
Stephen! Stephen!
撑住  撑住
Come on. Come on.
再往上一点
Just a little higher.
小心针头
Please be careful with the needle.
斯蒂芬
Stephen?
-这是什么  -我的魂体
- What am I seeing? - My astral body.
你死了吗
Are you dead?
不  克里斯汀  但我要死了
No, Christine, but I am dying.
对了
Right.
好吧
好  好吧
Yeah. All right. Okay.
我从没见过这样的伤口
I've never seen a wound like this.
你被什么刺伤了
What were you stabbed with?
我不知道
I don't know.
-我现在得消失了  -什么
- I'm gonna have to vanish now. - No, what?
别让我死  好吗
Keep me alive, will you?
好
Okay!
Okay.
糟了
Oh shit!
充电至200焦
醒醒  醒醒
Come on, come on.
斯蒂芬  醒醒
Stephen, come on.
再电我一次
Hit me again!
别这样
Stop doing that!
提高电压  再电我一次
Up the voltage and hit me again.
-不  你的心脏跳了  -照做吧
- No, your heart is beating! - Just do it!
天啊
Oh my God.
充电至360焦
不要碰触病人  按电击键
天啊
Oh god! Oh god!
-你没事吧  -嗯
- Are you ok? - Yeah.
好了
Okay.
过了这么久  你突然出现
After all this time, you just show up here,
魂体飞出身体
flying out of your body?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我也想你
I missed you too, by the way.
我给你发了邮件  你从来不回
I wrote you emails, but you never responded.
为什么要回
Why would I?
克里斯汀  我太抱歉了
Christine, I am so, so sorry.
我为一切道歉  你说得对
For all of it. I mean, you were right,
我是个彻头彻尾的混蛋  我对你太不好了
I was a complete asshole. I treated you so horribly
你应得到更好的对待
and you deserved so much more.
别说了  你显然是受惊了
Stop. You... you're clearly in shock.
到底怎么回事
I mean, what the hell is happening?
你去哪了
Where have you been?
西药没能治好我后
Well, after Western medicine failed me,
我去了东方  最终来到加德满都
I headed East, and I ended up in Kathmandu.
-加德满都  -对
- Kathmandu? - Yeah.
鲍勃·西格歌里唱的那个
What, like the Bob Seger song?
1975年的《美丽失意者》A面
1975, Beautiful Loser, side A. Yeah.
然后我去了一个叫卡马塔奇的地方
And then, I went to a place called Kamar-Taj
跟一位叫古一法师的人
and I talked to someone
聊了聊  然后
called the Ancient One, and...
-所以你加入了邪教  -不是
- So you joined a cult. - No, I didn't.
不算是
Not exactly. No. I mean,
他们确实教我挖掘
they did teach me to tap into powers
我之前闻所未闻的能量
that I never even knew existed.
-听起来就像是邪教  -不是邪教
- Yeah, that sounds like a cult. - It's not a cult.
-邪教徒就会这么说  -不
- Well, that's what a cultist would say. - Oh, no.
等等  斯蒂芬
Wait, Stephen, wait.
你想做什么
What do you think you're doing?
邪教集会我要迟到了
I'm late for a cult meeting.
-简直是疯了  -是啊
- This is insane. - Yeah.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
你能跟我说实话吗
Can you tell me the truth?
一位强大的魔法师
Well, a powerful sorcerer,
把自己献给了一个远古实体
who gave himself over to an ancient entity
他能打破物理法则
Can bend the very laws of physics,
还拼命想杀了我
tried very hard to kill me,
但我把他铐在格林尼治村了
but I left him chained up in Greenwich Village,
回到那个地方最快的办法是走传送门
and the quickest way back there is through a dimensional gateway
我在清洁间开了一个
that I opened up in the mop closet.
好吧  不说算了
Okay. Don't tell me. Fine.
我真的得走了
Really do have to go.
斯特兰奇
Strange!
你没事
You're okay.
相对而言  是的  我没事
A relative term, but yeah, I'm okay.
悬浮斗篷
The Cloak of Levitation.
它找上你了
It came to you.
了不起
No minor feat.
它可花心了
It's a fickle thing.
他逃走了
He's escaped.
-卡西利亚斯  -对
- Kaecilius? - Yeah.
他能随意折叠空间和物质
He can fold space and matter at will.
他能在镜像次元外折叠物质
He folds matter outside the mirror dimension?
-在真实世界中  -对
- In the real world? - Yeah.
-还有几个  -两个
- How many more? - Two.
我把一个丢在了沙漠里
I stranded one in the desert.
-另一个呢  -他的尸体就在大厅里
- And the other? - His body's in the hall.
多拉姆法师在门厅里
Master Drumm is in the foyer.
他被带回卡马塔奇了
He's been taken back to Kamar-Taj.
伦敦圣殿沦陷了
The London Sanctum has fallen.
只剩下纽约和香港的
Only New York and Hong Kong remain now
来抵御黑暗次元
to shield us from the Dark Dimension.
你保卫了遭受袭击的纽约圣殿
You defended the New York Sanctum from attack.
这里的法师走了  需要一位新的
With its Master gone, it needs another,
斯特兰奇法师
Master Strange.
不
No.
我是斯特兰奇博士
It is Dr. Strange.
不是斯特兰奇法师[硕士]或斯特兰奇先生
Not Master Strange, not Mr. Strange,
是斯特兰奇博士
Doctor Strange.
我成为医生时  曾发誓不伤害他人
When I became a doctor, I swore an oath to do no harm.
而我刚刚就杀了一个人  我不会做第二次了
And I have just killed a man! I'm not doing that again.
我当医生是为了救人而非杀人
I became a doctor to save lives, not take them.
你当医生主要是为了救一条生命
You become a doctor to save one life above all others.
你自己的
Your own.
还是能看穿我  是吧
Still seeing through me, are you?
我看到的是我一直所见的
I see what I've always seen.
你过于膨胀的自我
Your overinflated ego.
你想回到之前  你能够掌控一切的妄想
You want to go back to the delusion that you can control anything,
甚至掌控死亡
even death,
然而没人能控制死亡
which no one can control.
伟大的斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇博士也不行
Not even the great doctor Stephen Strange.
多玛姆也不行
Not even Dormammu?
他能让人永生
He offers immortality.
正是我们对死亡的恐惧给了多玛姆生命
It's our fear of death that gives Dormammu life.
-他以此为食  -正如你以他为食
- He feeds off it. - Like you feed on him?
你跟我说掌控死亡
You talk to me about controlling death.
我知道你是怎么做的
Well, I know how you do it.
我看过了《卡里奥斯特罗之书》里缺失的法事
I've seen the missing rituals from the book of Cagliostro.
千万当心你接下来要说的话  博士
Measure your next words very carefully, doctor.
因为你可能不喜欢听吗
Because you might not like them?
因为你可能不知道你在说什么
Because you may not know of what you speak.
-他在说什么  -我在说她的长命
- What is he talking about? - I'm talking about her long life.
她不死的缘由
The source of her immortality.
她从黑暗次元汲取能量来维持生命
She draws power from the Dark Dimension to stay alive.
那不是真的
That's not true.
我见过那些法事  想明白了
I've seen the rituals, worked them out.
我知道你是怎么做的
I know how you do it.
等他们重组  狂热信徒就会回来
Once they regroup, the zealots will be back.
你们会需要支援
You'll need reinforcements.
她不是你以为的那样
She is not who you think she is.
你没资格那么说
You don't have the right to say that.
你不知道她肩上担负的责任
You've no idea the responsibility that rests upon her shoulders.
对  我也不想知道
No, and I don't want to know.
-你是个懦夫  -因为我不是个杀手吗
- You're a coward. - Because I'm not a killer?
狂热信徒会把我们统统消灭
These zealots will snuff us all out,
而你却不能振作起来  先消灭他们
and you can't muster the strength to snuff them first?
-你以为我刚刚做了什么  -你救了你自己
- What do you think I just did? - You saved your own life!
然后像只受伤的狗一样不停抱怨
And then whined about it like a wounded dog.
而你就能轻松做到吗
You would have done it so easily?
你无法想象
You've no idea,
我做过的事
the things I've done...
答案是没错
And the answer is yes.
-毫不犹豫  -即使还有别的办法
- Without hesitation. - Even if there's another way?
-没有别的办法  -是你缺乏想象力
- There is no other way. - You lack imagination.
不  斯蒂芬
No, Stephen.
是你缺少骨气
You lack a spine.
他们回来了
They're back.
我们得了结此事
We have to end this.
快
Now!
斯特兰奇  下来战斗
Strange! Get down here and fight!
不要
No.
镜像次元
The Mirror Dimension.
你在这里无法影响真实世界
You can't affect the real world in here.
现在是谁得意呢  混蛋
Who's laughing now, asshole?
是我
I am.
我拿了他的悬戒  他们跑不了的  对吧
I've got his sling ring. I mean, they can't escape, right?
快跑
Run!
他们与黑暗次元的联系
Their connection to the Dark Dimension
使他们在镜像次元里更为强大
makes them more powerful in the Mirror Dimension.
他们不能影响真实世界  但还是能杀了我们
They can't affect the real world, but they can still kill us.
这并不明智
This wasn't cleverness.
这是自杀
It was suicide!
真好笑
That is hilarious.
这是个错误
This was a mistake.
是真的
It's true.
她真的从黑暗次元汲取能量
She does draw power from the Dark Dimension.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius.
我投奔你时
I came to you,
心碎
broken,
迷失
lost,
需要帮助
in need.
我信任你做我的导师  你却满口谎言
Trusted you to be my teacher, and you fed me lies.
我是想保护你
I tried to protect you.
-真相会伤害我吗  -你自己会
- From the truth? - From yourself.
如今我有新导师了
I have a new teacher now.
多玛姆在欺骗你
Dormammu deceives you.
你不知道他的真面目
You have no idea what he truly is.
他所谓的永生并非天堂  而是无尽的煎熬
His eternal life is not paradise, but torment.
骗子
Liar.
克里斯汀
Christine!
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
我的天
Oh my god.
不是心房颤动  她心肌顿抑
It's not fibrillation. She has a stunned myocardium.
-神经性休克吗  -对
- Neurogenic? - Yes.
拿棉签
Someone get the swabs.
尼克
Nic?
我们得降低她的脑压
We need to relieve the pressure on her brain.
她心率在下降
She's still dropping.
她快不行了
We're losing her!
得给她加氧
We need to increase her oxygen!
-急救车推过来  -她的瞳孔放大了
- I need a crash cart! - Her pupils have dilated!
无反射能力  也读不到脑部活动了
No reflexes. We're not reading any brain activity.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
别这样  你快死了
Come on. You're dying!
你得马上回到身体里  你没时间了
You have to return to your body now. You don't have time.
时间是相对的  你的身体还没倒地呢
Time is relative. Your body hasn't even hit the floor yet.
我花了太多岁月窥视未来
I've spent so many years peering through time,
看这一刻
looking at this exact moment.
却看不到之后
But I can't see past it.
我阻止了无数种可怕的未来
I've prevented countless terrible futures.
一次接着一次  永无休止
And after each one, there's always another.
都将我带到这一刻
And they all lead here,
但也止于这一刻
but never further.
你觉得自己死于这一刻
You think this is where you die.
想知道我在你的未来看到什么吗
You wonder what I see in your future?
不想
No.
想
Yes.
我从未看到过你的未来  只能看到其可能性
I never saw your future. Only its possibilities.
你有行大善的能力
You have such a capacity for goodness.
你总是很出众
You always excelled,
但并非因为你渴望成功
but not because you crave success,
而是因为你害怕失败
but because of your fear of failure.
正因此我才是一位优秀的医生
That's what made me a great doctor.
正因此你无法成就伟业
It's precisely what kept you from greatness.
傲慢和恐惧仍绊着你
Arrogance and fear still keep you
让你无法学会最简单也最重要的一课
from learning the simplest and most significant lesson of all.
是什么
Which is?
你并不重要
It's not about you.
你第一次来找我时
When you first came to me,
问我是如何治愈了乔纳森·潘伯恩
you asked me how I was able to heal Jonathan Pangborn.
我没有
I didn't.
他将次元能量引入体内
He channels dimensional energy directly into his own body.
-他靠魔法行走  -时刻如此
- He uses magic to walk. - Constantly.
他可以选择
He had a choice,
是回到原来的生活
to return to his own life
还是为比小我更伟大的事业做贡献
or to serve something greater than himself.
所以我的手能复原吗
So, I could have my hands back again?
我能回到从前的生活吗
My old life?
可以
You could.
而世界会因此变得更加危险
And the world would be all the lesser for it.
我厌恶从黑暗次元汲取能量
I've hated drawing power from the Dark Dimension.
但你知道
But as you well know,
人有时必须打破规则
sometimes one must break the rules
才能够成就伟大的事业
in order to serve the greater good.
莫多不会这么觉得
Mordo won't see it that way.
莫多的灵魂刚强不屈
Mordo's soul is rigid and unmovable,
那是他青春的火焰锻造的品性
forged by the fires of his youth.
他需要你的变通  就像你需要他的力量
He needs your flexibility, just as you need his strength.
你们只有共同努力  才有希望阻止多玛姆
Only together do you stand a chance of stopping Dormammu.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready.
没人会准备好
No one ever is.
时机由不得我们选
We don't get to choose our time.
是死亡赋予了生命意义
Death is what gives life meaning.
知道自己生命有限
To know your days are numbered,
人生苦短
your time is short.
按说都这么久了  我应该准备好了
You'd think after all this time I'd be ready.
但你看看我
But look at me,
无限延长片刻时间
stretching one moment out into a thousand,
就为了看雪景
just so that I can watch the snow.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-我不明白是怎么回事  -我知道
- I don't understand what's happening. - I know.
但我得走了
But I have to go away now.
你曾说失去我的手未必是末路
You said that losing my hands didn't have to be the end,
也可以是开端
that it could be a beginning.
对
Yeah.
因为还有其他方式可以拯救生命
Because there are other ways to save lives.
更艰难的方式
A harder way.
更怪异的方式
A weirder way.
帕尔默医生  请前往急诊室
Dr. Palmer, to the ER, please. Dr. Palmer, to the ER.
我不希望你走
I don't want you to go.
停下
Stop.
香港
好好选择武器
Choose your weapon wisely.
谁都别想闯进圣殿
No one steps foot in this Sanctum.
谁都别想
No one.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius.
你站错了队  王
You're on the wrong side of history, Wong.
-她死了  -你是对的
- She's dead. - You were right.
她并不是我以为的那样
She wasn't who I thought she was.
她很复杂
She was complicated.
复杂
Complicated?
黑暗次元不稳定
The Dark Dimension is volatile.
危险
Dangerous.
如果她被控制了呢
What if it overtook her?
她教导我们那是禁忌
She taught us it was forbidden,
她自己却汲取其能量  来盗取数世纪的寿命
while she drew on its power to steal centuries of life.
她做了她以为正确的事
She did what she thought was right.
代价终究会来
The bill comes due.
你还不明白吗
Don't you see?
她的犯忌导致狂热信徒投向多玛姆
Her transgressions led the zealots to Dormammu.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius
是她的错
was her fault.
而我们现在  就在面对她欺瞒的后果
And here we are, in the consequence of her deception.
浴火的世界
A world on fire.
莫多  伦敦圣殿已经沦陷
Mordo,London Sanctum has fallen.
纽约圣殿也两次遭到袭击
The New York one has been attacked. Twice.
你清楚他们接下来要去哪
You know where they're going next.
香港
Hong Kong.
你曾叫我战斗  就好像我命系于此
You told me once to fight like my life depended on it,
因为有一天  或许真会如此
because one day, it might.
那一天已经到来
Well, today is that day.
我不能一个人打败他们
I cannot defeat them alone.
圣殿已经沦陷
The Sanctum's already fallen.
黑暗次元
The Dark Dimension.
多玛姆来了
Dormammu is coming.
太迟了
It's too late.
没有什么能阻止他了
Nothing can stop him.
未必
Not necessarily.
不
No.
咒语起效了
The spell's working.
我们有第二次机会
We've got a second chance.
不
No!
王
Wong!
打破自然法则  我知道
Breaking the laws of nature, I know.
别现在停下
Well, don't stop now.
等圣殿复原
When the Sanctum is restored,
他们会再次发起攻击  我们得守住
they'll attack it again. We've gotta defend it.
走吧
Come on!
起来  斯特兰奇  起来战斗
Get up, Strange. Get up and fight!
我们可以做个了结
We can finish this.
你无法抵抗不可避免之事
You can't fight the inevitable.
多美啊
Isn't it beautiful?
超越时间的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
超越时间
Beyond time...
斯特兰奇
Strange!
他走了
He's gone.
就连斯特兰奇也抛下你们  屈服于他的力量
Even Strange has left you and surrendered to his power.
多玛姆  我来谈条件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你是来受死的
You've come to die.
你的世界现在是我的了
Your world is now my world,
就像所有世界一样
like all worlds.
多玛姆  我来谈条件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你是来受死的
You've come to die.
你的世界现在是我的了...
Your world is now my...
这怎么回事
What is this?
幻觉吗
Illusion?
-不  是真的  -那就好
- No, this is real. - Good.
多玛姆  我来谈条件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你...怎么回事
You've... what is happening?
就像你给卡西利亚斯你的次元的力量
Just as you gave Kaecilius powers from your dimension,
我也从我的世界带来了一份力量
I brought a little power from mine.
这是时间
This is time.
无尽循环的时间
Endless looped time.
你好大胆
You dare!
该死...
Oh, fu...
多玛姆  我来谈条件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你不能永远这么做
You cannot do this forever.
其实  我能
Actually, I can.
现在就这样了
This is how things are now.
你和我  困在这一刻里  无穷无尽
You and me, trapped in this moment, endlessly.
那你就永生永世地死吧
Then you will spend eternity dying.
是啊  但地球上的人都能得以存活
Yes. But everyone on Earth will live.
但你会受尽折磨
But you will suffer.
痛苦跟我很熟了
Pain's an old friend.
多玛姆
Dormammu!
-我来谈条件  -停下
- I've come to bargain. - End this!
多玛姆
Dormammu!
你永远不会赢的
You will never win.
是啊
No...
但我可以输
But I can lose.
一遍
Again,
又一遍
and again,
无穷
无尽  直到永远
and again, forever.
-那样你就是我的囚徒  -不
- And that makes you my prisoner. - No.
停下
Stop!
停下来
Make this stop!!!
放了我
Set me free!
不
No.
我来谈条件
I've come to bargain.
你想要什么
What do you want?
把你的狂热信徒从地球上带走
Take your zealots from the Earth.
结束你对我的世界的袭击
End your assault on my world.
永远别回来
Never come back.
照做  我就结束循环
Do it, and I'll break the loop.
起来  斯特兰奇
Get up, Strange.
起来战斗
Get up and fight!
我们可以做个了结
We can finish this.
多美啊
Isn't it beautiful?
超越时间的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
-你做了什么  -我谈妥了条件
- What have you done? - I made a bargain.
这是怎么回事
What is this?
这是
Well, it's,
你想要的一切
it's everything you've ever wanted.
永生  成为唯一的一部分
Eternal life as part of the One.
你不会喜欢的
You're not gonna like it.
你真该把整本书偷走的
You know, you really should have stolen the whole book,
因为警告
because the warnings...
警告是写在咒语后面的
the warnings come after the spells.
真好笑
That's funny.
我们成功了
We did it.
是啊
Yes.
我们成功了
Yes, we did it.
也是靠违反自然法则
By also violating the natural laws.
看看你周围  都结束了
Look around you. It's over.
你还是觉得不会产生后果吗  斯特兰奇
You still think there will be no consequences, Strange?
不会有代价
No price to pay?
我们跟她一样  打破了法则
We broke our rules, just like her.
代价终究会来
The bill comes due.
总会来的
Always.
总有清算的一天
A reckoning.
我不会再走这条路了
I will follow this path no longer.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
明智之举
Wise choice.
你今后还会有机会戴阿戈摩托之眼
You'll wear the eye of Agamotto
等你掌握其法力之后
once you've mastered its powers.
在那之前
Until then,
最好别戴着无限宝石满街乱跑
best not to walk the streets wearing an infinity stone.
什么
A what?
你或许有魔法天赋
You might have a gift for the mystic arts,
但你还有很多要学
but you still have much to learn.
古一法师的死
Word of the Ancient One's death
很快将在多元宇宙里传开
will spread through the multiverse.
地球没有至尊法师维护了
Earth has no Sorcerer Supreme to defend it.
-我们必须做好准备  -我们会的
- We must be ready. - We'll be ready.
奇异博士
地球上现在还有魔法师了
So, Earth has wizards now, huh?
喝茶吗
Tea?
我不喝茶
I don't drink tea.
你喝什么
What do you drink?
不喝茶
Not tea.
我有一份关注名单  都是来自
So, I keep a watchlist of individuals and beings
其他世界  可能对这个世界构成威胁的人
from other realms that may be a threat to this world.
你的领养弟弟  洛基  就是其中之一
Your adopted brother, Loki, is one of those beings.
-的确该加上他  -嗯
- Worthy inclusion. - Yeah.
为什么带他来纽约
So, why bring him here to New York?
这说来话长
It's a bit of a long story.
家庭闹剧  之类的
Family drama, that kind of thing, but...
我们在找我父亲
we're looking for my father.
好吧  如果你们找到了奥丁
Oh, okay. So, if you found Odin,
你们都会马上回阿斯加德吗
you'd all return to Asgard, promptly?
是的  马上
Oh, yes. Promptly.
太好了
Great.
我来帮你吧
Allow me to help you.
有事吗
Can I help you?
他们拿担架把你抬去了卡马塔奇
They carried you into Kamar-Taj on a strecher.
瞧瞧你现在的样子  潘伯恩
Look at you now. Pangborn.
莫多
Mordo.
我能为你做什么  哥们
So, what can I do for you, Man?
我离开了数月  想通了一件事
I've been away for many months now and I've had a revelation.
魔法师的真正意图
The true purpose of a sorcerer
就是扭曲事物应有的形态
is to twist things out of there proper shape.
盗取能量
Stealing power,
败坏自然
perverting nature...
就像你
like you.
我没偷什么  这是我的力量
I've stolen nothing. This is my power.
我的
Mine.
力量
Power...
是有目的的
has a purpose.
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为我终于明白这世界的问题出在哪了
Because I see at long last what's wrong with the world.
有太多魔法师
Too many sorcerers.
奇异博士还将回归